My brother sends his
apologies for not being here
and would like to invite all of
you to his home for a meeting.
All you have to do is sit with
Jack Nelson and talk about a...
new golden age.
If anyone is going to kill
Tommy Shelby... It will be you.
The future belongs to us.
Your daughter has Consumption.
Consumption is a very
infectious disease.
While they X-ray Ruby,
they have to X-ray us.
It'll be the girl's
mother who laid the curse.
Perhaps she waited until
your little girl was seven
so you'd know how it feels.
Now that I'm without whisky,
I can hear the spirits clearly
and they are saying Ruby will
be well if I make amends.
She's gone, Tommy.
This programme
contains some scenes
which some viewers may find
upsetting, strong language,
discriminatory language and content
and some scenes of a sexual nature.
Improved By M_I_S
www.opensubtitles.org
♪ In this heart lies for you
♪ A lark born only for you
♪ Who sings only to you
♪ My love, my love
♪ My love
♪ I am waiting for you
♪ For only to adore you
♪ My heart is for you
♪ My love, my love
♪ My love
♪ This is my grief for you
♪ I will have you with me
♪ In my arms only
♪ For you are only
♪ My love, my love
♪ My love. ♪
Arthur.
I've written some words.
I can't speak 'em.
You're the oldest.
You speak 'em for me.
I'm sorry, brother.
I can't do it.
We could have afforded
a golden carriage.
She deserved a golden carriage.
But we didn't afford
ourselves that luxury.
Because gold doesn't work.
That was the last lesson
that Ruby taught us.
This place was her favourite
place in the whole world.
And she used to say.
"Dad"
"you never know what's going
to come down the river."
And it's true.
Little Ruby's fate came a
thousand miles too soon.
But in her name and in her
memory things will change.
And whatever comes down the river
from now on we will make good
we will make peaceful
and honest and good
and send it on down the
river better than it was.
In her memory we will do this.
But for now, we send her
on, to wherever it is you go
in the hope that if
there is a destination
that it's a yard like this,
with horses...
and boats
for her to play on.
Tom, I've got the petrol.
Who will light the flame?
Jeremiah?
Jeremiah, you made her laugh.
You light the flame.
No, no! No! Lizzie...
No, you won't burn her! No!
Lizzie, shush, shush, shush!
I just want to see her.
I just want to see her face. We'll
go and see her together. Come on.
We'll go and see
her together. Yeah.
Oh, my baby.
The devils who did
this will pay, Ruby.
What do you mean?
Where are you going?
Riley.
I think the
police are here.
Evadne Barwell?
Yeah. Who's asking?
I am here on behalf
of the blue sapphire.
Don't shoot! There are babies!
♪ From the silence
♪ From the night
♪ Comes a distant lullaby
♪ Cry, remember that first cry
♪ Your brother standing by
♪ And lot of loved
♪ Beloved sons of mine
♪ Sing a lullaby
♪ Mother is close by
♪ Innocent date
♪ Such innocent eyes...
♪ Envy stole your brother's life
♪ Came home murdered
piece of mind
♪ Left you nightmares
on the pillow. ♪
Gold dust.
Our business is done,
Esme. Get out of the car.
Not quite done, Tommy.
I thought this would
be a good time.
In fact, it's the perfect time.
Some business is
still unfinished.
Christians say, "The Lord
gives, the Lord takes away."
Our spirits are the same.
Spirits just took
away your child.
Get out of the car, Esme.
But those same spirits want to
give you a different child, Tommy.
What child?
A daughter lost.
A son found.
Before you went to France,
a long time ago at Appleby
Fair you slept with a girl.
Her name was Zelda. I met her.
She said you slept together
under a hazel tree, May 1914.
When she fell pregnant, her
father threatened to kill you,
but you'd already joined the
army and gone away to France.
You remember the girl and the
hazel tree, don't you, Tommy.
Whoever that boy is, Esme
whoever he is, our business
is done here. I brought you
to this camp for a reason,
and I brought him as well.
He is yours.
A boy born with hazel eyes.
He calls himself Duke.
His mother is
dead. He's a thief.
He works the fairgrounds, but he
says he wants more to his life
than big wheels and carousels.
If the losing of Ruby has
left a hole in your heart
I'll send him to you.
If you give me a bit more gold
I'll tell him Tommy
Shelby can offer a man
far, far more than big
wheels and carousels.
Is our business
done or not, Tommy?
I know where you went.
I'm going to spend more
hours working in the Commons
with Mr Churchill.
His fight is my fight.
I sat like a stone and thought about
you killing someone in her name.
And the Shelby institutions
will be expanded.
I will set up a fund to research the
causes and cures for Consumption.
Did the woman you
kill have children?
10,000 children die every
year, Lizzie. Go to bed, Tommy.
I've been reading
about new research.
Stop and close your
fucking eyes. I will not...
I will not stop!
What is this good
that you will become?
I killed a woman.
I killed a woman and three men.
And their bodies will be
thrown aboard the boat,
like all the other bodies,
but I am stepping off that
boat and onto another boat.
Do you understand?
Yeah.
The doctor from the Sanatorium
called and said that he needs
to speak to you urgently.
But I think now you are beyond
the help of doctors. Lizzie...
Frances said Arthur's here.
Tommy?
Tom? Yeah, it's me.
Ah, fuck.
Arthur, give me a
light, will you?
I can't find my lighter.
I'm sorry I couldn't
speak at the wagon, Tom.
Don't be sorry.
What are you doing here?
Waiting for this
fucking cup to fill up.
Nearly empty, this barrel.
There are plenty
of barrels, Arthur.
Start another barrel.
I thought maybe they're
all full of fucking blood.
The junk, Tom
fucks you up your mind.
You know, Arthur.
You was already fucked up.
You was fucked up
since you were a kid.
This is my theory.
It's from that time I gave you
a beating when you
were 12 and I was nine.
We were fighting
over cigarettes.
Maybe
when I had you
down on the ground,
I gave you one too
many to the head.
It was a draw, though, Tom.
Nah,
I beat you.
I had you pinned.
You actually didn't.
We both agreed. You're so fucked,
you can't remember, brother.
I do. I do remember
little things.
I know you do.
So, do I.
The fog and the gas
is clearing, eh?
Here, that cup's nearly
full. Pass it here.
That's...
Tommy... stuff any more.
You don't drink no more, Tom.
After Polly was gone, Arthur.
I thought I could
just march and march.
I just kept up
that fucking left,
right, left, right, left,
right, fucking rhythm.
I'd never have to stop.
Then Ruby went.
I stumbled and crashed.
And now here I am
sat on my arse on the ground
like a fucking tunneller
with my old comrade Arthur.
Remember the January, Arthur?
The family boat?
The whole family
living on something
the size of ten of
these fucking barrels.
Remember that night
at Tile Cross,
16 of us sleeping on the
boat, the coppers come.
We all swam like rats.
Except for Arthur.
Arthur holds them off with
a boat hook, all on his own.
And I remember,
I climbed back up at
the lock and looked back
and saw you waving
that fucking boat hook
in the copper's faces
on your own.
That's when I realised.
When I had you on the ground
all them years ago,
it's because you let me win.
You wanted me to win.
You've wanted me
to win ever since.
What chance do I have... if you
start doing that again, eh?
You'll stop.
You'll stop cos the
family needs you to.
It's like that long tunnel
on the Dudley stretch.
You remember Dudley
canal, line number one?
3,172 yards of fucking pitch
blackness and rats swimming.
Yeah. Then we'd come round
that corner and there'd be
a shaft of light.
And then we'd know.
Yeah. And you and me would
both know it was nearly done.
That's where we are now, Arthur.
Just a few more yards to go.
Then you'll change your ways.
And I'll change
the fucking world.
♪ Like a slumber In the moss
♪ Like a display In the dark
♪ I have loved
you From the start
♪ But there's cold veneer
near the cloud of you
♪ Of you
♪ Oh
♪ Sit on back in thrones of blue
And inlay black, so righteous you
♪ Bear cold decree
♪ It's dead to me
♪ Sit on through while
your mistakes loom
♪ You're stone dead blind
and it's drowning all
♪ Your company. ♪
We assumed, at this late
hour, you would've had dinner.
There are drinks and sandwiches,
if you want. We're not here to eat.
Mr Shelby will be down shortly.
Please, tell Mr Shelby
on behalf of us all
that changing the
world can wait.
He doesn't want to wait.
There is Champagne.
Oh, goodie.
Charles?
I heard cars.
Mr Shelby, the guests are...
I know.
Dad
there's a Bentley
and a Rolls-Royce.
Yeah.
Go to bed, Charles.
I can't sleep.
I see her, when I shut my eyes.
Go to your mum.
She'll be awake.
She holds on to me.
Let her hold on to you.
You hear me?
Always let her hold on to you.
Go on.
Mr Shelby, the guests said
they would understand if...
Have you served
them drinks? Yes.
Yeah.
OK, Frances.
The agenda is in my head.
I'm OK.
Do I look OK?
If someone touches
you, you won't shatter.
Sing it.
Sing it. I love that song.
I...
can't be singing rebel songs in
a house in grief and mourning.
Sing it to me softly.
It breaks my heart.
Don't look at him. He's English.
He can block his ears.
Darling, should she sing her
rebel IRA song, while we wait
or would that be inappropriate?
You know I went to a meeting of
similar intent to this in Berlin.
Attended by the
Chancellor himself,
and Goering and Himmler.
It lasted until the sun came up.
We spoke about the future of
the world in a serious way.
When the first rays of
light entered the room,
we all stood and stared at it,
as if it were the world to come.
There was no
singing, no giggling.
And when breakfast was served on the
terrace, overlooking the mountains,
they brought up some Jews.
And while we ate our eggs,
they were forced to eat grass.
And we watched as we
sipped our coffee.
We should all remember
this is serious business.
Oh, Diana.
Now, look what you've done.
You have killed the mood.
Let her sing her fucking song to
raise our spirits. Go on, please.
♪ In a neat little
town they call Belfast
♪ Apprentice to
trade I was bound
♪ And many an hour's
sweet happiness
♪ Have I spent in
that neat little town
♪ A sad misfortune
came over me. ♪
♪ Blackbird, sit on my
shoulder and tell me a song. ♪
Did it break?
Mum will fix it for you.
♪ When I cry, do you hear in
colour or black and white, bird?
♪ The morning is new
but the feeling is old
♪ Intervene, blackbird,
and shorten the road
♪ Blackbird, the way I
imagined love was wrong
♪ I've come
♪ to love him like I
couldn't fathom, blackbird
♪ What I tap away
at I fear and I long
♪ Intervene, blackbird,
and shorten the road
♪ Blackbird, slip into my
slumber and show me a song
♪ When I dream
♪ Do you see in colour
or at all, bird?
♪ The picture is peaceful
but I dream alone
♪ Intervene, blackbird,
and shorten the road. ♪
She's not here any more.
♪ Her eyes, they
shone like diamonds
♪ I thought her the Queen. ♪
Mr Shelby. No, please,
no condolences.
Thank you all for coming.
Now, let's try to find out
how this new world of
ours will look, shall we?
Perhaps, Mr Mosley, we can
turn to what practical things.
Mr Nelson can do to further our
cause, while he's in the country.
It's me who has the ear of the
President of the United States.
Which is kind of
why I'm here, right?
We do, indeed, have things for you
to whisper into the President's ear.
Tell him we are England.
We are the mood England is in.
And in Ireland, appeasers
to the English abound
but we represent the true liberated
spirit of the country that
populated your own.
I hear about communists
in both places.
We are the bulwark against them.
When it comes to
the working class,
we could move our people
from Republicanism
to Fascism with just a nudge.
They trust us.
You ride with hounds, Mr Mosley.
Will you hunt communists?
Oh, my hounds are baying.
Shelby
you run as a socialist.
Mr Shelby has one of the largest
Commons majorities in England.
In the heart of England.
When the time comes, he'll
resign his party whip
and run as an independent.
But underneath, do you truly
believe in the cause, Mr Shelby?
I'm here.
Mr Nelson, I'm
here four nights...
Four nights after and I am here
in this room, in this meeting,
I am here and I am serious.
Prove it to him.
Prove it physically.
Perish Judah.
That thing is going
to get us killed.
Go to bed.
At school, they've
stopped talking to me.
They say the black rubs off.
When they come to power,
they'll take her off you.
They're going to
separate us all out.
They'll send her to Africa.
Yeah?
And where will they send you?
Where will they send you, Karl?
You're half Gypsy, so
to Egypt maybe?
Something I never
told you before
because it wasn't important.
Maybe now, it is.
Your dad was Jewish.
He was the son of a
tailor in Stechford.
They changed their
name to Thorne
to stop the bricks coming
through the window.
So, where will they
send you, Karl?
Mr Nelson, you can report
back to your President
that the aristocracy and
the meritocracy are united
in their conviction that
a new order is coming.
Also, Mr Nelson, at present our
weapons are coming from Germany.
The British are closing
our supply lines down.
We would value a
supply from Boston.
Weapons, I can give you, if
they're to be used in a good cause.
And while on the subject
of import and export,
Mr Shelby, in light of
our new relationship,
and since you have
proven your commitment
in a most extraordinary way,
Boston is now officially open for
the importation of your merchandise.
Good.
If we have established what
we came here to establish,
perhaps we should
all say goodnight.
Absolutely.
That's the same typewriter you
bought me all those years ago
to help me become respectable.
Do you remember?
Yeah.
This arrived.
It's from the sanatorium.
I've already paid
Ruby's medical bills.
I don't think it's a bill.
It says it's urgent. It's
from the senior consultant.
Why didn't you come to bed?
I'm typing up my
recollection of the meeting.
If I... if I do
it straight away,
I can quote people
word for word.
The information is more
useful to Mr Churchill
if it is word for word.
I burnt her chair.
The paint on the wood
left a smell in the air.
I didn't open the window.
I quite like the smell.
Not yet.
I have this work to
do cos now I know
that I will change.
That I have to change.
And change for good...
Lizzie.
Not just yet.
Hello?
Oh.
♪ She had a heartful
of love and devotion
♪ She had a mindful
of tyranny and terror
♪ Well, I try I do, I really try
♪ But I just...
Baby, I do, I error
♪ So, come and find
me my darling one
♪ I'm down to the
grounds the very dregs
♪ Here she comes
blocking the sun
♪ Blood running down
the inside of her legs
♪ The moon in the sky
is battered and mangled
♪ And the bells from the
chapel go jingle-jangle
♪ Jingle-jangle, jingle-jangle
Jingle-jangle, jingle-jangle
♪ Do you love me?
♪ Do you love me? ♪
I saw him leave.
He keeps this apartment expressly
for this purpose, doesn't he?
Are you following me, Mr Shelby?
I'm flattered,
but why?
When I do business with someone,
I make it my business
to know their secrets.
Mosley's reputation
is no secret.
Not him, you.
How did you know I'd come here?
I know things.
I read people's minds, you know.
Little glances across
tables. It's a gift.
The whole family
witches and sorcerers.
Your uncle will disown you.
Fucking his business
partner behind his back.
You think he has morals?
He's a Catholic.
Men do what they want,
women do what they are told.
Will you tell Michael?
Michael is family.
We are a family healed.
You have no interest in me,
or in Michael.
So, why don't you just tell
me what you actually want?
You will be with Mosley
when he's in Berlin.
You'll be in the room,
when he meets senior members
of the German Government.
I want to know
what is discussed,
and I want to know
what is decided.
And if I lie?
I will know.
You know Michael thinks
you're the devil,
and I think he might
actually be right.
That was the other
reason I came here.
What are Michael's real
intentions toward me, Gina?
And if you lie, I will know.
Tommy
he intends to complete the deal.
And then, you both walk away.
Fuck.
Come.
Mr Shelby, Doctor Holford.
Send him in.
You said it had to be in person.
Here I am.
You might want to sit down.
Mr Shelby, I know that you are
still grieving for your daughter,
but I have news
that cannot wait.
When you were X-rayed and examined
at the sanatorium ten days ago
there was no TB
found in your lung.
But I am afraid they
found something else.
Something related to
your daughter's illness.
They tried to speak
to you at the hospital
but you were not co-operating.
After your daughter's death,
you could not be found
to be informed in person.
Eventually, as your personal
doctor, they called me.
I didn't offer you tea. You look
like death. Do you want tea?
No.
At the sanatorium, they
conducted blood tests.
The tests suggest that
the shadow you can see
at the base of your skull
is not cancer.
It is tuberculoma.
A tubercular growth caused
by the same bacteria as TB.
You may have picked it
up from your daughter.
Once this disease enters a
household, it can run wild.
It can be transmitted
with a simple kiss.
It seems the Shelby
household is no exception.
Mr Shelby, as I say, I am aware
that you are still grieving,
but you must understand
this is very serious.
From the size of the tumour,
expansion must've been rapid.
I have no doubt that you are
already experiencing symptoms?
Have you recently
suffered seizures?
Bouts of weakness,
dissociation, hallucinations?
Why didn't you come and see me?
I have work to do.
Am I a danger to others?
No.
Unlike TB, tuberculoma
is not infectious.
Mr Shelby,
it is not infectious,
but in your case.
I am afraid it is inoperable.
The growth is in
your brain stem.
Any attempt to remove it
would result in trauma
and brain haemorrhage.
Whilst you were
refusing my calls,
I showed your X-rays to three of
the best surgeons in the country.
They all said they
would not operate
as it would be futile.
Of course, you will want a
second opinion for yourself.
Doctor Helen Rutherford
at St Thomas'.
She is a friend.
This...
How bad will it get?
As the tumour grows,
the rate of physical and mental
deterioration will increase.
Eventually, you will need
people around you constantly,
who love you very much.
How long?
I understand you have defeated
many enemies, Mr Shelby.
Now, you have a new one
inside you.
You cannot defeat it,
but you can keep it
at bay for a while.
If you live correctly, if you are
determined and if you fight...
I asked you a question.
So, I want an answer.
I don't want your
fucking platitudes.
How long before I need people
around me, who love me very much?
Sorry. It's fine, Lizzie.
My accountant here
was just leaving.
I will telephone you,
when I get back to London.
No, I don't have enough time.
You're an accountant, give
me a fucking number now.
One year.
Perhaps 18 months.
That's fine. That's
all I need to know.
I will adjust my finances
accordingly. Thank you.
I will write to you, explaining the
full implications. Yeah, thank you.
Good day.
Something serious?
No, no, just a
just a bill I wasn't
expecting and I...
I'll have to pay it.
Will you give me a
minute on my own, Lizzie?
Yeah.
Not a devil
just an ordinary mortal man.
There will be a
war in this family,
and one of you will die.
Polly.
Just give me enough time
to do what I have to do.
Kill.